

Nicolas Barbey

a 36 Rue du Maréchal Foch 95120 Ermont
 ② +(33) 6 22 61 33 94

- ☐ https://github.com/nbarbey

À Propos

I am a staff, an architect and an experienced developer in C, Python and go.
I am specialized in software development methods.
Especially methods which emerged from the schools of software craftmanship and "extreme programming".
I am experienced in the domains of identity, authentication and authorization.
I approach architecture through Domain Driven Design and

Domain Driven Design and software patterns that allow for continuously evolving architectures.

Skills

Go, Python, C TDD
Architecture DDD
Security Authn/Authz
Methods Teaming

Experience

Staff Engineer - leboncoin, 2024 - now

Teaching and mobbing with developers

Architect – leboncoin, 2022 – 2024 DDD, Continuous Delivery, evolving architecture, coaching.

Back-end developer go – leboncoin, 2016 – 2022 Authentication, authorization, identity, scalability, methods.

C Developer - Exosec, 2015 - 2016 Observability application development

C Developer - Intersec, 2013 - 2015 High-performing application development

Developer for image processing – Intitek, 2012 – 2013 Embedded algorithms

Image processing engineer – DxO Labs, 2011 – 2012 Design of algorithms with Python

Post-doctorat – CEA, *2009 – 2011*

PhD - CNES, 2006 - 2008

Education

Institut d'Optique Graduate School, 2002 - 2005

Louis-le-Grand, 2000 - 2002

ENCPB, 1999 – 2000

Lycée Claude Monet, 1992 - 1999